# **Iosif Vigh**

## Senior Software Engineer

London, UK

Github: iosify in LinkedIn: iosify 🚵 StackOverflow: iosify

I am a Senior Software Engineer with extensive experience in developing end-to-end projects using Node.js and Laravel. I prioritise writing clean, maintainable code to ensure ease of maintenance and quick onboarding for junior developers. With a natural curiosity and a commitment to continuous learning, I am always exploring new technologies and methodologies to enhance my skills and contribute effectively to my team and stakeholders. I'm currently working on an open-source personal learning project using T3Stack with NextJS, tRPC, Drizzle ORM and Clerk while deploying to Vercel with Github Actions.

#### **SKILLS Frameworks Dev-Ops** Languages Laravel Express Node.js Javascript Serverless AWS Terraform CI/CD Typescript PHP Solidity Hardhat Github Actions Vercel bash Docker **Architectures Databases ORMs** MySQL PostgreSQL MVC Microservices Eloquent Doctrine Drizzle MongoDB AuroraDB Serverless Client server Prisma DynamoDB Redis SOLite **Event-driven**

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE (7)**

Aug 2018 - Current

Contractor Software Engineer at Casa4 - own LTD (London, UK)

Provided contractor services through my own LTD, Casa4, in between other roles. The following is a list of the most notable projects, specializing in Laravel and Node.js. Involved both in team-based development and solo application building from design to deployment and maintenance.

- Artetra (NodeJS, React, ThreeJS, Solidity, Hardhat, Express, Postgres, MongoDB, AWS, Docker)
  - As an **Acting CTO**, I was responsible with converting business requirements into project features by overseeing the application architecture. I managed a team of 3-4 developers and provided them with necessary assistance. The ecosystem consisted in a backend Express API which connected to blockchain a smart contract written in Solidity, a frontend React app which had a 3D part written in ThreeJS. The project was deployed to an AWS infrastructure using Docker.
- ElectroRent (Laravel, MySQL, SQLite, Bash)
  - As a **Backend Engineer** I worked on the API of a large tool renting platform built with Laravel. Responsibilities included designing and implementing new API endpoints, creating database migrations, building new features, debugging complex issues, and optimizing performance across critical application areas.
- Aliat Optic (NodeJS, Serverless Framework, Lambda, DynamoDB, AWS, MySQL, Laravel, DigitalOcean)

As a **Solution Architect** I designed and developed an invoicing app, integrating external FTP data via AWS Lambda and DynamoDB. This application was successfully used in production for about 3 years with minimal maintenance, demonstrating reliability and efficiency.

Hurlingham Club (Laravel, Laravel Forge, Laravel Envoyer, MySQL, AWS, Docker)

As a **Backend and DevOps Engineer** I led the migration of a large application from from a paid provider to the client's own servers. My responsibilities included provisioning the new infrastructure, setting up de CI/DC pipeline, updating the code from PHP5.5 to PHP8.1, updating all the dependencies to the latest stable versions, making sure no data was lost in the DB and creating diagrams to explain each step of the process to the stakeholders.

■ TicketTailor (PHP, MySQL, SQLite)

As a **Backkend Engineer** I worked on the API of a large ticketing application built in PHP. Designed and implemented a testing framework using PHPUnit to automatically scan OpenAPI specs and validate each API endpoint, including all new additions. This significantly improved deployment times combined with strategically assigning tests to the appropriate level (unit, integration, acceptance). Also contributed by adding numerous endpoints to the client-facing API.

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022

#### **Software Engineer** at True Compliance (London, UK)

Contributed to the development of a cloud-based compliance management system, enhancing compliance tracking and reporting capabilities.

- Developed the main API of the system and contributed to designing the ecosystem's serverless architecture, leading to a robust and scalable solution.
- Created a reporting application that enabled non-technical stakeholders to preview any key metrics.
- Also built a bespoke real-time caching system that stores processed relational data in a NoSQL database.
   The purpose of this was to vastly increase the speed of the system and reduce the load on the database.
- → Technologies: Laravel, Laravel Vapor, AWS, SQS, VueJS, Node.js, Serverless Framework, CLI, Bash

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

#### **Software Engineer** at Skin Analytics (London, UK)

Designed and developed main applications and maintained AWS infrastructure, contributing to the company's mission of improving skin health.

- Led the migration from a NoSQL database to a relational database, resulting in an 11x speed increase without affecting the frontend or user experience.
- Green State State

Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

#### **Application Developer / Dev-Ops** at Woooba (London, UK)

Sole Backend Engineer responsible for designing, developing, and supporting client applications, driving business growth.

- Developed and maintained nationwide educational platforms, enhancing the learning experience for thousands of users.
- Built a comprehensive financial management application with Laravel and Vue.
- Managed all DigitalOcean droplets with a CI setup ensuring reliable and efficient deployment processes.
- → Technologies: Laravel, DigitalOcean, Laravel Forge, MySql, VueJS

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016

#### PHP Application Developer at iQU Group (Amsterdam, NL)

Marketing solutions for game developers.

- Created complete APIs from start to end as well as libraries which were used by my colleagues.
- Another smaller project was built with Java and PipelineDB.
- Technologies: PHP, Laravel, Symfony, API, MySQL, Git, Docker, CLI, PhpUnit, AngularJS, Java

Oct 2014 - Nov 2015

**PHP Application Developer** at Project 89109 (Amsterdam, NL) Online dating services.

■ 

→ Technologies: PHP, API, MySQL, CLI, Git, JS, jQuery.

Nov 2017 - Current

Hardware Engineer / Dev-Ops at Hidden Hash (Cluj-Napoca, RO)

Family business dealing with mining crypto-currencies.

- Worked on Business model, Legal compliance, setup, Software & security optimization/tweaks/updates,
   Performance fine tuning.
- Built an open-source watchdog mechanism: github.com/iosifv/amd-vega-startup-scripts

#### PROJECTS (3) -

#### Recspenses

https://www.github.com/iosifv/recspenses/

 A production-ready financial web application to calculate recurring monthly expenses. Initially started as a training project to practice my full-stack skills. Features include: a simple UI, multi-currency support including cryptocurrencies and an intuitive tagging system for expense labeling.

I used the "T3 Stack" which is a web development stack made focused on simplicity, modularity, and full-stack typesafety. The full technology list is: NextJS, tRPC, TypeScript, NodeJS, Clerk, Drizzle ORM, PostgreSQL, Tailwind CSS, Vercel, GHA

#### **CLI Path**

 Created a CLI tool to check Google Maps API directions, with saved locations, authentication, and a custom serverless API layer to simplify token management - built for training, touching multiple technologies: Nodels, Serverless Framework, AWS, Auth0, OpenAPI, VHS, npm, GHA

#### Casa4 website

• An overengineered personal website built for learning purposes. Themed with *Hugo*, built with *Terraform* and *Cloudfront*, deployed to *AWS S3* with *Github Actions*.

### EDUCATION (2) -

2012 - 2010

Masters Management and Business Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

Operations Management Business Analytics Marketing Fundamentals Human Resource Management

Operations Management

2004 - 2009

Bachelor of Engineering Computer Science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

Object-oriented programming Data Structures and Algorithms Advanced Databases Computer Networks C++

Java NET SQL Lisp Prolog Xilinx Assembly x86 processor Electronics Physics Mathematics

#### INTERESTS

## **Hobbies**

Motorcycles Photography

Chess HiFi Audio Boxing